Of All the Crooked Men in All the Crooked West One of Them Was the Best!
There Was a Crooked Man... is a western film directed by Joseph L. Mankiewicz.
A charming but ruthless criminal is sent to a remote Arizona prison, where he enlists the help of
his cellmates in an escape attempt with the promise of sharing his hidden loot.
Paris Pitman, Jr., played by Kirk Douglas.
Woodward W. Lopeman, played by Henry Fonda.
Dudley Whinner, played by Hume Cronyn.
Floyd Moon, played by Warren Oates.
The Missouri Kid, played by Burgess Meredith.
Cyrus McNutt, played by John Randolph.
There Was a Crooked Man...
is a 1970 American Western film directed by Joseph L.
Mankiewicz and starring Kirk Douglas and Henry Fonda.
It was the only western made by Mankiewicz.
It was written by David Newman and Robert Benton, their
first script after Bonnie and Clyde.
The film explores themes of prison, prison escape, criminal, warden.